<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wild and Radiant Me</title>
    <description>Blog of Random art projects. Painting, Drawing, Sewing, Technology, Etc.
</description>
    <link>http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 15:39:17 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 15:39:17 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bash Script for Simple Screenshot Utility</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s post is less artsy and less projecty. I’m going to be walking through a bash script I wrote. My hope is to be able to explain it to people who are still in the learning stages, much like I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been (slowly, but surely) making my way through the JavaScript lesson on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;. There’s hints and a link to a Q&amp;amp;A forum, but sometimes I get help from friends through IRC. (Come hang out with us. Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://hashbang.sh&quot;&gt;hashbang.sh&lt;/a&gt; and follow the command). When I get help from friends, I can pretty easily give them the code through places like &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com&quot;&gt;Pastebin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://pae.st&quot;&gt;pae.st&lt;/a&gt;, but usually my problem is stemming from unclear instructions (codecademy does well, but sometimes I think being so far away from the beginning there’s some miscommunication). Once I’ve given my friend a link to the code I then either have to paraphrase what the instructions are or copy the instructions to a google doc and send that to them somehow. It just takes too long and can be somewhat frustrating. You might be wondering, “why don’t you just ‘print screen’?” well, I have the image, but they still don’t. I still need to upload it somewhere, send them a way to get there, etc etc. This is where I started brainstorming a solution. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing was to figure out the steps I wanted my future script to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It would need to create a new folder like .screenshots, but only if it wasn’t already created (you know, for the 2nd, 3rd, 4th, etc time around).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I would need a variable for a unique file name. Easiest is probably the date and time, so for example 2015-02-09-16-25-33.png. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It would need to import the image and save it to the .screenshot folder with the generated filename.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It would need to make a url so that I could share the screenshot and, to make sharing even easier, already have the url in my clipboard so all I’d have to do after selecting my screenshot is paste it where I want. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most, if not all, scripts will have variables. Basically just like what you learn in your first algebra class and probably even before then. It’s just like 1/2b * h to find the area of a triangle. b meaning the base and h meaning the height. And you just substitute the numbers in. Turns out the majority of this screenshot script is variables. You’ll see that at the beginning of my script I have my list of variables. This is so a new person using my script only has to change the specific names of things once instead of every time they show up in the script.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stinethebean3/screenshot&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to my script on github for you to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a folder only if it doesn’t already exist. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick Google search I found that &lt;code&gt;mkdir -p &quot;VARIABLE&quot;&lt;/code&gt; is all that is needed. &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/59838/check-if-a-directory-exists-in-a-shell-script&quot;&gt;Stack overflow&lt;/a&gt; had the answer. &lt;code&gt;mkdir&lt;/code&gt; is a command used to “make (a) directory” and &lt;code&gt;-p&lt;/code&gt; “means make parent directories as needed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;code&gt;mkdir -p&lt;/code&gt; you’d put the directory name, but it’s a variable, so you’d change it at the top where the list of variables are. Mine is in my home folder under the folder name of .screenshot (a . in front of a file/folder will make it hidden).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;mkdir -p &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;$SCREENSHOT_DIR&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also made a symbolic link for a shortcut command to only have to type &lt;code&gt;ss&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;screenshot&lt;/code&gt; each time I wanted to run the script just by writing this command in the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln -s screenshot.sh ss
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import (save) the screenshot to the folder. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This step is pretty simple. It’s just the word &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; and then the variable for your directory/filename. The / represents the inside of the folder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;import &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;$SCREENSHOT_DIR/$SCREENSHOT_FILE&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The filename will be a variable because each time you take a screenshot the image will need to have a different name else it the 2nd screenshot will overwrite the 1st one.  I went with the date and time down to the seconds because it is possbile you may want to take multiple screenshots in a minute. So the variable becomes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;SCREENSHOT_FILE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;$(date +%y-%m-%d-%H-%M-%S).png&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copy the file to a public directory on a web server for easy sharing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The command for that is &lt;code&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt; which means “secure copy” (to another computer). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;scp &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;$SCREENSHOT_DIR/$SCREENSHOT_FILE&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;$SSH_USERNAME@$SSH_HOSTNAME:$PUBLIC_FOLDER&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is copying the file, which is found in that specific directory, over to your server. I decided to go with my own public webserver over something like &lt;a href=&quot;imgur.com&quot;&gt;Imgur&lt;/a&gt; because imgur may not always be here (or might change their API a.k.a. how to post to their website). I can however make sure that my own personal server stays up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Echo the url and send to clipboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were to type &lt;code&gt;ss&lt;/code&gt; into the command line in a terminal it would output the url there, just as sort of a check and balances that it worked. But you don’t have to go into the terminal to run this command. I use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://awesome.naquadah.org/&quot;&gt;Awesome window manager&lt;/a&gt; and just have to press win-r for run and type &lt;code&gt;ss&lt;/code&gt; there. Most window managers have a similar shortcut to “quick run” a command. (Alt+F2 does the same thing in Ubuntu for instance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;echo &quot;$FULL_URL&quot; | xclip&lt;/code&gt; is there to send the url to your clipboard so you only have to paste the url. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run the command you’re cursor will become a crosshair. Just click and pull what you want to screenshot. It doesn’t even have to be the whole page. Then it’s already created the filename and copied it to your clipboard. Easy-peasy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a random &lt;a href=&quot;http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/15-02-09-15-34-43.png&quot;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt; I took while finalizing this blog post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bye!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/bash/script/simple/coding/screenshot/2015/02/09/screenshot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/bash/script/simple/coding/screenshot/2015/02/09/screenshot.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>bash</category>
        
        <category>script</category>
        
        <category>simple</category>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>screenshot</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Soda Can Earrings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 2015! Which everyone knows will be the year of funky fresh fashion according to Back to the Future II, right? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-btf_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fashion in BBF2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe not, but I recently saw a photo on Pinterest of a pair of earrings fashioned from an Arizona Tea can. The cherry blossom design is quite pretty. But I of course thought to myself, “I can do that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only soda cans in my home happen to be Surge and Bawls. The nerdiest, techiest of drinks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got my tools out and started cutting open the cans and cutting out designs using (so far) 2 techniques. I made 3 different types of earrings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-1_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finished Surge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-2_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finished Bawls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took some tutorial pictures showing the first pair I made, so you can make your own! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a soda can&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sharp scissors (I used kitchen shears) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an exacto knife&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a design hole puncher (The only one I have right now is a 1” circle)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a small hole puncher (mine is ‘bead landing’ brand) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a couple jewelry tools (Probably also bead landing. They have everything.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an emery board (or sand paper)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some earring parts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and a surface you’re ok with cutting into. (I used some plywood)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-3_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tools1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-4_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tools2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-5.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-5_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tools2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First step is to cut apart the can. Be careful because the can will most likely become very jagged. Cut one end off, then make a slit down the can away from any parts you might make into an earring, then cut the other end off. Cut off any jagged pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-6.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-6_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cutting Can1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-7.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-7_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cutting Can2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-8.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-8_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cutting Can3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might want to find something heavy to hold down the can as it will keep its roundedness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;right&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-9.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-9_thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you want to cut out a design for the earring. I used the exacto knife to cut out some rectangles. I haven’t gotten adventurous yet. For the Bawls can I used the 1” hole punch for both earrings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you slice you can usually just peel the aluminum apart. You don’t necessarily have to cut all the way through with the knife. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;left&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-11.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-11_thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll want to use the emery board or sandpaper on the corners and perhaps on the edges a bit. The last thing you want is to be constantly poked in the neck while wearing your snazzy earrings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you’ll use the small hole punch to make holes for the jump rings. I just eyeballed where to punch. You’ll want the holes relatively close to the edge so there’s room to work in the jump ring. If you don’t understand what I mean, you will once you try it. And it’s ok to mess up a few times. (I still do!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-12.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-12_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Punching&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-13.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-13_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Punching&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-14.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-14_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Punching2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next is adding some beads. I figured a biggish one or a few small ones would need to be on the bottom to prevent the earring from flapping around too much. I decided to stick to Surge colors for these. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used a headpin for the bottom bead. These have a little flat head to keep the bead on. You’ll have to cut off the excess then use the curling tool to make a loop. How much to leave on is also something I eyeball and will still get wrong a lot. So again don’t worry about messing up a few times. When it comes to making the loop that is something you will begin to “feel.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are pins that come with a loop on one side. For my green and red beads I used this, cut off the extra, and made the second loop on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-15.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-15_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beads&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-16.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-16_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beads2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sce-17.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sce-17_thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beads3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture on the right is the “blueprint” of my earring. Just connect everything together and you’ve got yourself an earring! Make a second one for a pair! What’s cool about the Surge can is that each earring is unique. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Bawls can I have only used the barcode and the inside of the can because I haven’t quite figured out what I want to do with those “eyes.” I want to get some different design hole punches to try out as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too bad, right? See what you can make! If you do make your own - post a picture. I love seeing how different people come up with different designs and ideas on how to go about doing something. Perhaps you’ve figured out a better way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bye!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 16:20:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/crafts/jewelry/nerd/2015/01/27/sodacanearrings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/crafts/jewelry/nerd/2015/01/27/sodacanearrings.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>crafts</category>
        
        <category>jewelry</category>
        
        <category>nerd</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Techy Door Wreath</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When my husband and I moved into our apartment here in California I noticed that a few of the other residents had door wreaths, which made me want one. I knew that I needed to make something that both my husband and I would enjoy. I wasn’t going to succumb him to something flowery or otherwise “girly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So of course I went the technology route. I ended up taking apart my DVD player since we have a XBox we can play DVDs in. But that only gave me about 3-4 good pieces to work with. I found it amusing that the word “Play” was misspelled on the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/play.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DVD&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was trying to figure out a way to get a bunch of computer parts for cheap I at least got the wreath itself ready. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Michael’s the craft store I got an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.michaels.com/M10375063.html#q=wreath&amp;amp;start=5&quot;&gt;Ahland Straw Wreath Form&lt;/a&gt; in 12 inches. Then I took a black sparkly ribbon also from Michael’s at 2.5 inches wide and wrapped it around the wreath using needles with heads every so often to keep the ribbon in place.  For hanging the wreath I pinned the two ends of a black ribbon about .5 inches wide into half a loop onto what would be the back of the wreath. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the tech part. Some friends came over and they asked if we had been to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weirdstuff.com&quot;&gt;Weird Stuff&lt;/a&gt; yet. We had not even heard of the place yet. It’s basically a big warehouse full of mainly old computer stuff. Everything from wires to full computers to a bucket of nuts and bolts 50 cents a scoop to all the things I ended up buying for the wreath. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wreath1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Assembly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I laid everything out on the table that I was planning on using for the wreath. The things from Weird Stuff I got for $20. Not pictured is a keyboard and a couple other small things for future projects. So really, like, $17. Then I placed things on the wreath overlapping like a collage and just seeing how I liked the look of something somewhere and took a picture of that. I took every thing off, plugged in the heat gun, then glued everything into place using the photo as a reference. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the end result:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wreath2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finished&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up using one of those &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.command.com/wps/portal/3M/en_US/NACommand/Command/Products/Catalog/~/Command-Designer-Medium-Hooks?N=5924736+3294529207+3294773807&amp;amp;rt=rud&quot;&gt;Command Strips&lt;/a&gt; to hang the wreath on the door. I believe that is the exact kind I bought. The wreath is kind of hefty. We tested the hook with a bag of 10 pound rat food overnight and it held. So even though it says 3 pound weight limit, it’s fine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the hook holds it up well that doesn’t prevent someone from accidentally knocking it down by hitting it with their backpack &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; husband &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt;. A few items fell off including two of the projector light bulbs, but thankfully they didn’t break and I was able to just re-glue what fell off back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there you have it! A Techy Door Wreath! 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wreath3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Door&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know in the comments if you would like to see more progress pictures. Taking progress pictures is something I’m not used to doing, but I also don’t want to start if people find it annoying. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 12:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/door/decorations/wreath/tech/art/2014/11/04/wreath.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/door/decorations/wreath/tech/art/2014/11/04/wreath.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>door</category>
        
        <category>decorations</category>
        
        <category>wreath</category>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>art</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twinkle, Twinkle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, welcome to my blog of things. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured as a first blog/test blog I’ll post something I’ve done in the past. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost a year ago I was speaking to my then boyfriend (now husband) about LEDs and making them blink. I looked up at a painting I had done a few years previous of an astronaut floating in space with a quote from one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VCOIjvWFFo8&quot;&gt;The Hoosiers&lt;/a&gt; songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked if I could make the stars actually twinkle and he said, “sure!” And so it began…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this was the point in which he had me learn how to solder via a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10547&quot;&gt;SparkFun Simon game&lt;/a&gt;. Then he showed me the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arduino.cc/&quot;&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt; software and walked me through how to write a script to make the stars randomly blink at different light levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adafruit.com/products/1138&quot;&gt;AdaFruit Neopixel LEDs&lt;/a&gt; and tested them along the way. Finally glueing them to the back of the canvas, allowing the light to shine through by poking a hole for each star with a thumbtack. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I have the whole thing hooked up to a 12 volt battery, but those are a little expensive and only last about 6 hours total. What I want to do is hook it up to an actual plug and have it on a light sensor to just turn on at night. Or something like that instead of a switch and battery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/twinkle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front and Back&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more images: &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/2GmzC&quot;&gt;Imgur Gallery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for Twinkle: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/stinethebean3/6400059&quot;&gt;Github Gist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/painting/leds/tech/art/2014/08/23/twinkle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/painting/leds/tech/art/2014/08/23/twinkle.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>painting</category>
        
        <category>leds</category>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>art</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
