<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wild and Radiant Me</title>
    <description>Blog of Random art projects. Painting, Drawing, Sewing, Technology, Etc.
</description>
    <link>http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 17:59:24 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 17:59:24 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Techy Door Wreath</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When my husband and I moved into our apartment here in California I noticed that a few of the other residents had door wreaths, which made me want one. I knew that I needed to make something that both my husband and I would enjoy. I wasn’t going to succumb him to something flowery or otherwise “girly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So of course I went the technology route. I ended up taking apart my DVD player since we have a XBox we can play DVDs in. But that only gave me about 3-4 good pieces to work with. I found it amusing that the word “Play” was misspelled on the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/play.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DVD&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was trying to figure out a way to get a bunch of computer parts for cheap I at least got the wreath itself ready. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Michael’s the craft store I got an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.michaels.com/M10375063.html#q=wreath&amp;amp;start=5&quot;&gt;Ahland Straw Wreath Form&lt;/a&gt; in 12 inches. Then I took a black sparkly ribbon also from Michael’s at 2.5 inches wide and wrapped it around the wreath using needles with heads every so often to keep the ribbon in place.  For hanging the wreath I pinned the two ends of a black ribbon about .5 inches wide into half a loop onto what would be the back of the wreath. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the tech part. Some friends came over and they asked if we had been to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weirdstuff.com&quot;&gt;Weird Stuff&lt;/a&gt; yet. We had not even heard of the place yet. It’s basically a big warehouse full of mainly old computer stuff. Everything from wires to full computers to a bucket of nuts and bolts 50 cents a scoop to all the things I ended up buying for the wreath. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wreath1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Assembly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I laid everything out on the table that I was planning on using for the wreath. The things from Weird Stuff I got for $20. Not pictured is a keyboard and a couple other small things for future projects. So really, like, $17. Then I placed things on the wreath overlapping like a collage and just seeing how I liked the look of something somewhere and took a picture of that. I took every thing off, plugged in the heat gun, then glued everything into place using the photo as a reference. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the end result:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wreath2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finished&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up using one of those &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.command.com/wps/portal/3M/en_US/NACommand/Command/Products/Catalog/~/Command-Designer-Medium-Hooks?N=5924736+3294529207+3294773807&amp;amp;rt=rud&quot;&gt;Command Strips&lt;/a&gt; to hang the wreath on the door. I believe that is the exact kind I bought. The wreath is kind of hefty. We tested the hook with a bag of 10 pound rat food overnight and it held. So even though it says 3 pound weight limit, it’s fine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the hook holds it up well that doesn’t prevent someone from accidentally knocking it down by hitting it with their backpack &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; husband &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt;. A few items fell off including two of the projector light bulbs, but thankfully they didn’t break and I was able to just re-glue what fell off back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there you have it! A Techy Door Wreath! 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wreath3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Door&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know in the comments if you would like to see more progress pictures. Taking progress pictures is something I’m not used to doing, but I also don’t want to start if people find it annoying. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 12:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/door/decorations/wreath/tech/art/2014/11/04/wreath.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/door/decorations/wreath/tech/art/2014/11/04/wreath.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>door</category>
        
        <category>decorations</category>
        
        <category>wreath</category>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>art</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twinkle, Twinkle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, welcome to my blog of things. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured as a first blog/test blog I’ll post something I’ve done in the past. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost a year ago I was speaking to my then boyfriend (now husband) about LEDs and making them blink. I looked up at a painting I had done a few years previous of an astronaut floating in space with a quote from one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VCOIjvWFFo8&quot;&gt;The Hoosiers&lt;/a&gt; songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked if I could make the stars actually twinkle and he said, “sure!” And so it began…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this was the point in which he had me learn how to solder via a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10547&quot;&gt;SparkFun Simon game&lt;/a&gt;. Then he showed me the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arduino.cc/&quot;&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt; software and walked me through how to write a script to make the stars randomly blink at different light levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adafruit.com/products/1138&quot;&gt;AdaFruit Neopixel LEDs&lt;/a&gt; and tested them along the way. Finally glueing them to the back of the canvas, allowing the light to shine through by poking a hole for each star with a thumbtack. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I have the whole thing hooked up to a 12 volt battery, but those are a little expensive and only last about 6 hours total. What I want to do is hook it up to an actual plug and have it on a light sensor to just turn on at night. Or something like that instead of a switch and battery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/twinkle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front and Back&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more images: &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/2GmzC&quot;&gt;Imgur Gallery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for Twinkle: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/stinethebean3/6400059&quot;&gt;Github Gist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/painting/leds/tech/art/2014/08/23/twinkle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stinethebean.hashbang.sh/painting/leds/tech/art/2014/08/23/twinkle.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>painting</category>
        
        <category>leds</category>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>art</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
